A Guide to the Additional Papers of Nancy Hale
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Nancy Hale
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3646-g, 3646-h
This collection consists of ca. 450 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
3646-g was a gift of Nancy Hale Bowers, August 11, 1958. 3646-h was a gift of Nancy Hale Bowers, December 14, 1959.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains manuscripts, typescripts and galley proofs of novels and short stories as well as notes, clippings, correspondence with publishers and literary agents, and letters from friends, readers. and directors or attendees at various writing programs. Included are the typescript of Dear beast, and galleys of A New England girlhood and Heaven and Hardpan farm.
Correspondents, usually represented by one or two letters, include Frank [X] Barron, Mariesta Bloom, Catherine Drinker Bowen, Fredson Bowers, Constance Carrier, Charles Scribner's Sons, Mary Ellen Chase, John Ciardi, Robert M. Coates, George G. Coughlin, Richard Frede, Daniel Fuchs, John Holmes, Katie Letcher, Victoria Lincoln, William Maxwell, Mary Margaret McBride, James Mconkey, Elizabeth Nowell, Harold Ober, Theodore Peterson, John Lowell Pratt, santha Rama Rau, Nancy Wilson Ross, May Sarton, William Seward, William Sloane, Hollis Summers, Joyce Warren, James Wharton.
The collection also contains phonorecords of a 1950 interview with Hale, "Author meets the critics" and readings from Little Boy & his grandmother and Uncle Paul.
Contents List
- William Maxwell to Nancy Hale (Bowers) 1957-1958, 51 TLS (Box 1)
- Elizabeth Nowell to Nancy Hale 1957-1958, 41 TLS, ANS, ALS (Box 1)
- Mary Ellen Chase to Nancy Hale 1957-1958, 2 ALS (Box 1)
- Anita Black ( The Daily Progress) to Nancy Hale n.d., 1 ALS, 1 TLS (Box 1)
- Ned Bradford (Little, Brown and Co.) to Nancy Hale 1957-1959, 6 TLS (Box 1)
- R.H. Fetridge, Jr. (Little Brown and Co.) to Nancy Hale 1959, 2 TLS (Box 1)
- Dorothy Olding to Nancy Hale 1959, 1 TLS (Box 1)
- Ivan von Auw Jr. to Nancy Hale 1957-1959, 27 TLS (Box 1)
- Harold Ober to Nancy Hale 1946-1957, 4 TLS (Box 1)
- John Ciardi ( Saturday Review) to Nancy Hale 1957-1958, 5 TLS (Box 1)
- George H. Freitag to Nancy Hale 1957, 2 TLS (Box 1)
- Catherine Drinker Bowen to Nancy Hale 1959, 1 TLS (Box 1)
- Theodore Peterson to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 1)
- Mary Margaret McBride to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ANS (Box 1)
- Philip Lasell to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ALS (Box 1)
- To Nancy Hale from Ivan von Auw J., Clara Dowell; "an admirer" 1956-1959, 3 telegrams (Box 1)
- Clara Nowell to Nancy Hale 1957, 2 ALS (Box 1)
- Marion Benasutte to Nancy Hale 1957-1958, 2 TLS (Box 1)
- Mrs. Lewis Patton to Nancy Hale 1957-1959, 3 ALS (Box 1)
- John Holmes to Nancy Hale 1957-1958, 2 TLS (Box 1)
- Helene E. Tash to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 1)
- Charles Scribner's Sons to Nancy Hale 1955-1958, 12 TLS (Box 1)
- Muriel Lawrence to Nancy Hale 1957, 1 ALS, 1 TLS (Box 1)
- May Sarton to Nancy Hale 1957, 1 TLS (Box 1)
- John Lowell Pratt (A.S. Barnes and Co.) to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 1)
- Richard Frede to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 1)
- James Wharton to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ALS (Box 1)
- Robert Kaback to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ALS (Box 1)
- Forrest H. Graves to Nancy Hale 1958-1959, 2 TLS (Box 1)
- Nancy Wilson Ross to Nancy Hale 1957, 2 TLS (Box 1)
- Mrs. Dana Knowlton to Nancy Hale 1956-1958, 4 TLS (Box 2)
- To Nancy Hale re: The Prodigal Woman 1957-1959, 5 ALS (Box 2)
- To Nancy Hale re: Dear Beast1959, 3 ALS (Box 2)
- To Nancy Hale re: Her books 1958-1959, 6 ALS (Box 2)
- To Nancy Hale re: Heaven and Hard Pan Farm 1957-1958, 2 ALS, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- To Nancy Hale re: Her magazine stories 1956-1959, 19 ALS and TLS (Box 2)
- Shirley Molner to Nancy Hale re: Family Genealogy 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Constance Carrier to Nancy Hale 1957, 1 ANS (Box 2)
- Gertrude H. Hale to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- George Coughlin to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Miriam H. Flick to Nancy Hale 1959, 1 ALS (Box 2)
- Vera Malone Conrad to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Joyce Warren to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ALS (Box 2)
- James McConkey to Nancy Hale 1959, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Hollis Summers to Nancy Hale 1957, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- William Sloane to Nancy Hale 1957, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- C.N. Waldron to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Velma M. Boaz to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ALS (Box 2)
- Katie Letcher to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- William S. Seward Jr. to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Frank Barron to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- miscellaneous letters, cards, clippings, etc. ca. 1957 (Box 2)
- 5 TLS to Miss Frances Herman re: complimentary copies of Heaven and Hardpan Farm1957, 5 TLS (Box 2)
- Fredson Bowers to Nancy Hale 1958, TLS (Box 2)
- Elder to Fredson Bowers 1958, TLS (Box 2)
- two posters announcing lecture by Nancy Hale at University of Chicago 1958 (Box 2)
- Constance Smith to Nancy Hale 1957, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Mariesta Bloom to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ALS (Box 2)
- Florine Mac Conochie to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ALS (Box 2)
- Winifred McCulloch to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Ken Browne to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Margaret Tobin Vail to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- George N. Dale to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 TLS (Box 2)
- Mrs. Carl Burger to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ALS (Box 2)
- Rosamond Vitale to Nancy Hale 1958, 1 ALS (Box 2)
- Vicky Lincoln to Nancy Hale 1959, 3 TLS (Box 2)
- To Nancy Hale re: A New England Girlhood 1958-1959, 16 ALS and TLS (Box 2)
- Coming Out, TmsS, 3 versions with autograph corrections 8, 11, 9 pp. (Box 3)
- A Haunting, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 3)
- A New Place (The Keeper of the Horses), TMs, with ANS William to Nancy, 20 pp. (Box 3)
- comments on A New Place by William [Maxwell], TMs, 4 pp. (Box 3)
- A New Place (The Keeper of the Horses), TMs, 20 pp. (Box 3)
- The Keeper of the Horses (A New Place), TMs, 19 pp. (Box 3)
- The Keeper of the Horses, TMs, 18 pp. (Box 3)
- A Child's Garden of the Irish, TMs, several drafts, ca. 40 pp. (Box 3)
- A Child's Garden of the Irish, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 3)
- Secrets, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 3)
- Secrets, TMs, 14 sheets (Box 3)
- There is a Host Approaching Nigh, galley proof, 7 sheets, with TNS W. to Nancy (Box 3)
- Another Family, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 3)
- Another Family, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 3)
- Another Family, TMs, 13 pp. with TLS, William to Nancy (Box 3)
- Child Training at Harvard, TMs, 25 sheets (Box 3)
- Child Training at Harvard, working vari proof, 12 sheets (Box 3)
- Child Training at Harvard, galley proof, 6 sheets (Box 3)
  with TLS William to Nancy and exerpt of letter from Frederic H. Powell
- Miss August, mimeographed typescript, 14 pp. (Box 3)
- Life Later, TMs, 21 sheets (Box 3)
- lecture on Why did you have to write about such unpleasant characters?, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 3)
- The Boil, TMs, ca. 25 sheets (Box 3)
- The Boil, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 3)
- The Territory of Fiction, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 3)
- The Hidden Approach, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 3)
- The Object, newspaper and magazine clippings, galley proof, 18 sheets (Box 3)
- Dear Beast, TMs, 253 pp. (Box 3)
- Dear Beast, TMs, first draft, ca. 250 pp. (Box 4)
- Dear Beast, TMs, pp. 1-60. (Box 4)
- Flotsam, TMs, 13 pp. (Box 4)
- The Ages of Woman (Rich People), TMs, with extensive autograph corrections, 26 pp. (Box 4)
- Rich People, TMs, pp. 1, 2 ,7 ,18 ,30 ,21 ,22 ,23 ,24 (Box 4)
- The Problem of Bernadine, TMs, ca. 25 sheets (Box 4)
- agreement between Houghton Mifflin Company and Nancy Hale to publish A Summer's Long Dream in The Best American Short Stories, 19571957 Sept. 6 (Box 4)
- agreement between Charles Scribner's Sons and Nancy Hale to publish a book of short stories 1955 Jan 3 (Box 4)
- memorandum of agreement between Nancy Hale and Gollancy Ltd., for publication of A New England Girlhood1958 Feb. 14 (Box 4)
- It Was Just a Game, TMs, 3 pp. with autograph notes and newspaper clippings (Box 4)
- I read your book...., TMs, 20 pp. (Box 4)
- I read your book...., TMs, 4 seets (Box 4)
- story ideas, notes, other miscellaneous material, AMs, typescript fragments, ca. 200 items (Box 4)
- lecture about attitudes towards literature, TMs, 12 sheets (Box 4)
- True Fidelity [?] or The Unfaithful [?] or Truth [?], TMs with extensive autograph corrections, ca. 25 sheets (Box 4)
- A Slow Boat to China, TMs, 14 pp. (Box 5)
- A Slow Boat to China, TMs, 15 pp. (Box 5)
- What Makes a Memory Unforgettable, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 5)
- What Makes a Memory Unforgettable, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 5)
- Absolutely No Psychology, TMs, 21 pp. plus carbon, 21 pp. (Box 5)
- Another World, TMs, 7 pp. (Box 5)
- My Sister Kate, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 5)
- A Letter Home, TMs, 6 pp. with carbon copy 6 pp. (Box 5)
- Lawyer Leith, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 5)
- The Cruel, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 5)
- Eastern Point, TMs, 9 pp. (Box 5)
- All Things Lovely, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 5)
- One Touch of Malice, TMs, 14 pp. (Box 5)
- Mother, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 5)
- The Child Within, TMs, 24 pp. with carbon 24 pp. (Box 5)
- The Young Girl, TMs, 15 pp. (Box 5)
- A Change of Attire, TMs, 15pp. (Box 5)
- Are Philosophers People, TMs, 26 pp. (Box 5)
- The Ghost of Anne (Box TMs, 22 pp.)
- To Kill a Cat, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 5)
- Souvenir of Dr. Grady, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 5)
- poems The Road to Life The Maple Sugar Girls at Maple Inn, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 5)
- Before the Train, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 5)
- The King of Fancy's Daughter, galley proof, 10 sheets (Box 5)
- Introduction to A New England Girlhood, TMs, rough draft, 11 sheets (Box 5)
- Introduction to [A New England Girlhood], TMs, 5 pp. (Box 5)
- A New England Girlhood, galley proof, 92 sheets (Box 5)
- Heaven and Hardpan Farm, galley proof, 70 sheets (Box 5)
- Heaven and Hardpan Farm, galley proofs, ca. 70 sheets (Box 5)
- An Introduction to Glamour, galley proofs, 8 pp. with TLS W. to Nancy (Box 5)
- Recordings of some of Nancy Hale's short stories, 5 records
- Between the Dark and the Daylights, 1 reel of recording tape
- The Great-Grandmother, 1 reel of recording tape